<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ghost Journal</string>
    <string name="SpiritDesc">A Spirit is the most common Ghost you will come across, however it is still very powerful and dangerous. They are usually discovered at one of their hunting grounds after an unexplained death.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Nothing
        \n\nWeaknesses: Using Smudge Sticks on a Spirit will stop it from attacking for a long period of time.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Spirits, when smudged, are repelled for 180 seconds or about 3 minutes compared to other ghosts, which are typically repelled for 90 seconds 1 min and 30 sec.
    </string>
    <string name="WraithDesc">A Wraith is one of the most dangerous Ghosts you will find. It is also the only known Ghost that has the ability of flight and has sometimes been known to travel through walls.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Wraiths almost never touch the ground meaning it can\'t be tracked by footsteps.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Wraiths are afraid of Salt and will actively avoid it.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Wraiths can go through walls outside of hunts but not during hunts.
        \n\n\u2022 Wraiths teleport, often showing EMF Level 2, 25% chance of Level 5.
        \n If EMF level 2 occurs far from ghost room, possibly a Wraith.
        \n\n\u2022 Wraiths no longer step in salt altogether
        \n\n\u2022 Using salt in the Summoning Circle before summoning can help identify a Wraith.
        \n\n\u2022 Salt + motion sensors on a doorway. If ghost avoids salt but triggers sensors, likely Wraith.
    </string>
    <string name="PhantomDesc">A Phantom is a Ghost that can possess the living, often summoned by an Ouija Board. It induces fear in those around it.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Looking at a Phantom considerably drops your sanity.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Taking a photo of the Phantom makes it temporarily disappear.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Longer blink in hunts 1 to 2 seconds, nearly invisible during hunt.
        \n\n\u2022 Disappears if you photograph during event
                Electronic equipment malfunctions wil stop.
                Players will no longer hear their heartbeats if they happen.
                The audio of the event continues to play throughout its duration.
        \n\n\u2022 If you take a photo of a Phantom, the ghost won\'t appear in the image.
        \n\n\u2022 Phantoms can wander to a random player\'s location anywhere on the map.
        \n\n\u2022 Sanity drops twice as fast when looking at a Phantom.
        \n\n\u2022 Phantom\'s infrequent visibility during hunts makes tracking difficult.
        \n\n\u2022 Looping the ghost is challenging and not recommended.
        \n\n\u2022 Using Incense to blind the Phantom requires caution, smudging earlier than usual to avoid surprise. Stand at the end of a long hallway for safety.
             </string>
    <string name="PoltergeistDesc" formatted="false">A Poltergeist, also known as a noisy ghost, manipulates objects to spread fear.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: A Poltergeist can throw large amounts of objects at once.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Rooms with no movable objects.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Throws items, reduces player sanity by 2% per throw.
        \n\n\u2022 100% chance to throw objects during hunts, every .5 seconds.
        \n\n\u2022 Can create an "explosion" of items in the ghost room.
        \n\n\u2022 Scatter objects in the room to trigger the Poltergeist\'s throwing ability.
        \n\n\u2022 Look for objects being flung with force or multiple objects thrown simultaneously.
        \n\n\u2022 Create small spread-out piles for better detection.
        \n\n\u2022 Be cautious of inconclusive behavior; random interactions can mimic Poltergeist activity.
        \n\n\u2022 Low activity doesn\'t rule out the possibility of a Poltergeist.
        \n\n\u2022 Increase activity by turning off the lights.
        </string>
    <string name="BansheesDesc">The singing siren, known for attracting its victims through song. It has been known to single out its prey before making a killing blow.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Banshees will weaken their target before striking.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Banshees can sometimes be heard screaming with a parabolic microphone.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Hunts triggered at 50% sanity.

        \n\n\u2022 A Banshee aggressively hunts the target player in the building. If the player isn\'t present, it hunts others normally.
        \n\n\u2022 Banshees can wander near their target and enter hunt mode if in their line of sight.
        \n\n\u2022 Banshees initiate hunts when players enter the building with the low sanity target inside, ignoring avg sanity levels.
        \n Can hunt from 87.5% to 12.5% average sanity.
        \n Target\'s sanity drops 15% if specific ghost event conditions are met.
        \n\n\u2022 Roaming ability has 67% chance to target player during roam.
        \n Roaming doesn\'t leave EMF reading, unlike Phantom\'s ability.
        \n\n\u2022 Focuses on one player inside the house.
        \n Hunts like a regular ghost if target leaves.
        \n\n\u2022 Ignores non-targets during hunts.
        \n\n\u2022 More singing ghost events likely.
        \n\n\u2022 Distinct parabolic mic sound: scream.
        \n 33% chance of unique shriek-like sound
        \n\n\u2022 Use players as bait with Incense or planned escapes to identify target.
        \n Bait players attract the ghost using talking or electronics.
        \n Multiple players can do this to see who the Banshee targets.
        \n Useful when sanity-based method is unclear or on Nightmare difficulty.
        \n All players should be indoors for the test.


    </string>
    <string name="JinnDesc">A Jinn is territorial and attacks when threatened. It can travel at high speeds and is limited by cutting off power via the breaker box.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: The Jinn moves faster the further the target is.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Cutting off power limits the Jinn\'s speed.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Breaker on + Line of sight = Increased speed (not as fast as a Revenant or slow without LOS)
        \n\n\u2022 Turn off the breaker to disable Jinn\'s ghost powers.
            \n But this makes lights go out and sanity drains. Candles can help counter sanity loss.
        \n\n\u2022 Jinn has a 25% chance to drop a player\'s sanity within 3 meters.
         \n\ will give an emf reading at the breaker when this ability is performed
        \n\n\u2022 Within 3m of player = Normal ghost speed during hunt
        \n\n\u2022 To identify Jinn: During a hunt, observe speed change in a long room with clear line-of-sight. If it instantly speeds up upon seeing you, it\'s likely a Jinn. Be cautious if testing its speed within 3 meters.
        \n\n\u2022 Another way to identify Jinn: Leave a EMF reader at fuse box; if it detects reading without box changing, it\'s likely Jinn\'s ability, ruling out other causes.
    </string>
    <string name="MareDesc" formatted="false">A Mare primarily attacks in the dark. Keeping lights on and avoiding dark areas lowers aggression, but it attempts to turn off lights to hunt.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Attacks more in the dark, switching off lights.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Keeping lights on.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Hunts at 60% with lights off, 40% with lights on
        \n\n\u2022 Can\'t turn on lights
        \n\n\u2022 Higher light breaking event chance
        \n\n\u2022 Wanders more with lights on in its room
        \n\n\u2022  Nearby light turns on, Mare might quickly turn it off
        \n 10-second cooldown, resets if light turned on again
        \n Applies to lights, TVs, and computers
        \n\n\u2022 Mare prefers hunting with lights off, so keep lights on in its favorite room and nearby areas to reduce hunt threshold.
            \n Once Mare\'s sanity threshold is below 40%, it hunts regardless of lights. Leave lights off in its favorite room to concentrate its hunting there.
        \n\n\u2022Frequent room changes and wandering into unexplored dark areas may indicate a Mare if lights are usually kept on near the ghost. Especially in Professional and Nightmare

    </string>
    <string name="RevenantDesc">A Revenant is a ghost that can attack indiscriminately regardless of sanity levels when hunting. Hiding from the Revenant causes it to move slowly, but it travels faster than any other ghost if it\'s hunting a victim.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Attacks anyone regardless of sanity levels; can switch targets while hunting.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Moves extremely slowly when players hide.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Track ghost speed through video cameras to identify if it\'s a Revenant.
        \n\n\u2022 Sacrifice/delegate a fellow ghost hunter to investigate its speed during a hunt.</string>
    <string name="ShadeDesc">A Shade is considered a "shy ghost." It won\'t attack if multiple people are nearby, but it\'s harder to find in larger groups.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Extremely shy, hard to find and detect.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Doesn\'t hunt when players are in a group.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Shade hunts at average sanity below 35%.
        \n\n\u2022 Shades have a VERY LOW chance of hunting when multiple people are nearby, but it\'s not impossible.
        \n Turn off lights, avoid entering ghost room to provoke interactions.
        \n\n\u2022 Shadow form in ghost events or more airball events.
        \n Shade\'s shadow appearance from cursed items not guaranteed.
        \n\n\u2022 Event chance rises with lower average sanity.
        \n\n\u2022 Won\'t throw objects in the same room.
        \n\n\u2022 Won\'t hunt with a nearby player.
        \n\n\u2022 Test by staying in ghost room with a crucifix.
        \n\n\u2022 Low sanity, no hunt or crucifix use? Likely a shade.
        \n\n\u2022 Summoning Circle, Music Box, Monkey Paw can reveal black shadow appearance.
        \n Restores full visibility when hunt starts.


    </string>
    <string name="DemonDesc">A Demon is one of the worst ghosts to encounter.
        Highly aggressive, it attacks more often than any other ghost.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Can hunt at 70% sanity, with rare early hunts
        \n\n\u2022 Short 20-second hunt cooldown (others 25 seconds)
        \n\n\u2022 Smudging stops demon for 60s (others 90s, spirit 180s)
        \n\n\u2022 A crucifix is recommended to prevent hunts. stops demon within 5m (others 3m)
        \n A hunt close to a crucifix suggests it might not be a demon.

</string>
    <string name="YureiDesc">A Yurei is a type of ghost that drains player\'s sanity quicker than any other ghost. Smudging the room prevents it from moving for a long time.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Drains player sanity quickly.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Using a smudge stick in the same room stops the Yurei from moving.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Yureis drain sanity during hunts if you\'re within 10 meters.
        \n\n\u2022 Zaps 15% nearby player sanity
        \n\n\u2022 Ability closes room door
        \n All ghosts, including Yurei, can shut doors as part of their behavior. Yurei might do it more often due to its sanity drain ability.
        \n Yurei\'s ability affects tent doors, not locker or closet doors.
        \n\n\u2022 Smudge traps Yurei in Ghost room for 60 sec
        \n\n\u2022 Keep doors open near the ghost to observe its ability.
        \n\n\u2022 If a front door closes fully without a ghost event or hunt, it\'s definitely a Yurei.
        \n\n\u2022 Verify ghost interaction with EMF Reader to know if ghost touched door.
        \n\n\u2022 Yurei only closes doors, doesn\'t open them.


    </string>


    <string name="OniDesc">An Oni is a very active ghost, likely to show itself within the first few minutes of the game. It often wanders around near the ghost room. It\'s recommended to hide in a closet and wait for it to leave.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Oni are more active whilst people are nearby and will drain their sanity faster when manifesting.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Oni disappear less often while hunting their prey.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks`
        \n\n\u2022 Can\'t trigger "ghost mist”/"airball" event, fog ball approaches, hiss sound on collision. Chasing events can also hiss.
        \n\n\u2022 During Manifestation events: full form shown, not shadowy/translucent.
        \n\n\u2022 During Hunts: Oni is Visible longer dosent blink as often, easier to take photo of.
        \n\n\u2022 Double sanity drain during ghost events.

    </string>
    <string name="YokaiDesc">A common type of ghost attracted to human voices, often found in family homes.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Talking near a Yokai angers it and causes it to attack more often.
        \n\nWeaknesses: While hunting, it can only hear voices close to it.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 50% sanity hunt or 80% when players talk nearby
        \n\n\u2022 Voice and equipment detection within 2.5m during hunts
        \n\n\u2022 Increased activity when talking near a Yokai
        \n\n\u2022 Test by hiding, yelling/walkie during a hunt; , if ghost is not attracted = likely Yokai
        \n\n\u2022 Music box proximity before breaking is closer
        \n\n\u2022 If Monkey Paw unblocks hiding, ghost hears speech/electronics globally, overrides Yokai weakness.
    </string>
    <string name="HantuDesc">A rare ghost found in hot climates, known to attack more often in cold weather.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Moves faster in colder areas.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Moves slower in warmer areas.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Keeping the breaker on slows down the Hantu by keeping the house warm.
        \n\n\u2022 Hantu speed increases as temperature lowers.
        \n\n\u2022 No gradual speed increase with line of sight.
        \n\n\u2022 If you see Ghost breath during hunt Most likely Hantu
        \n\n\u2022 Breaker turn-off chance higher.
        \n\n\u2022 Breaker off, freezing breath in any room during hunt.
        \n\n\u2022 Freezing temps always in Nightmare mode.
        \n\n\u2022 Avoid ghost room during hunts. Light Snow raises danger.
        \n\n\u2022 Leaving the breaker on creates high temps slower ghost for looping
        \n\n\u2022 Loop around furniture during warm hunt; slow speed = Hantu.
        \n\n\u2022 Freezing breath in dark (breaker off) also IDs Hantu (riskier)
        \n\n\u2022 Raiju mimics speed with electronics; remove for clarity.
        \n\n\u2022 Moroi speeds up via lowering average sanity.



    </string>
    <string name="MylingDesc">A Myling is a very vocal and active ghost. It\'s quiet when hunting its prey.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Quieter when hunting.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Mylings frequently make paranormal sounds.
     \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
    \n\n\u2022 Stealthy ninja assassin
    \n\n\u2022 Heard within 12 meters during a hunt (footsteps and vocal noises)
    \n\n\u2022 Other ghosts heard up to 20 meters
    \n\n\u2022 Myling responds more on parabolic microphone
    \n\n\u2022 Test: Hide with flashlight/dots, if only footsteps when equipment flickers, likely a Myling
    </string>
    <string name="GoryoDesc">Using a video camera is the only way to view a Goryo when it passes through a DOTS projector.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: A Goryo usually only shows itself on camera if no people are nearby.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Rarely seen far from its place of death.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Goryo\'s dots visible only through video camera.
        \n\n\u2022 Dots won\'t appear if you\'re in the same room.
        \n\n\u2022 Check for Goryo: no players in room, use camera for dots.
        \n\n\u2022 Dots forced evidence in Nightmare mode.
        \n\n\u2022 No dots without video camera means no Goryo.
        \n Visible D.O.T.S. evidence on camera but not to naked eye = likely Goryo.
        \n D.O.T.S. seen without camera = not Goryo. Adjust brightness for clarity.
        \n\n\u2022 Goryo stays in its room, consistent favorite room.
        \n Sanity wish from Monkey Paw overrides this.
        \n\n\u2022 Tough to identify on 0 evidence runs. Observe favorite room change or use sensors/salt.

    </string>
    <string name="ObakeDesc">Obake are shape-shifters, taking on many forms, including humanoid shapes.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: When interacting with the environment, an Obake rarely leaves a trace.
        \n\nWeaknesses: This ghost will shapeshift, leaving behind unique evidence.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Unique 6-fingered fingerprint
        \n Two fingerprints on light switch
        \n Five fingerprints on keyboards and Prison doors (instead of four)
        \n\n\u2022Normal fingerprints don\'t rule out an Obake.
        \n\n\u2022 Forced fingerprints as evidence on Nightmare
        \n\n\u2022 25% chance of not leaving fingerprints
        \n\n\u2022 Ability to halve fingerprint duration
        \n\n\u2022 During hunts, Obake can shapeshift briefly
        \n\n\u2022 Flash as another ghost model of same gender
        \n\n\u2022 6.66% chance to shapeshift with each blink during hunt
        \n\n\u2022 Test Obake by looping and observing model change
        \n\n\u2022 Can change ghost model stance during hunt
        \n\n\u2022 Test by having it run from corridor to check blink change
        \n\n\u2022 Inconsistent fingerprints suggest an Obake; no prints, then prints on different surfaces.
        \n\n\u2022 Difficulty settings can affect fingerprints and decay timers.
    </string>

    <string name="OnryoDesc">The Onryo, "The Wrathful Spirit," steals souls to seek revenge. It fears fire and avoids it.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Extinguishing a flame can cause an Onryo to attack.
        \n\nWeaknesses: When threatened, this ghost is less likely to hunt.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Can hunt at 60% sanity
        \n\n\u2022 3 extinguished flames trigger hunt (Any Sanity)
        \n\n\u2022 Can\'t hunt within 4m of flame
        \n\n\u2022 Test with candles, crucifixes in room
        \n Crucifix without candle, not onryo
        \n Crucifix after blowing candles, likely onryo
        \n\n\u2022 May wander, initiate hunt away from candles
        \n\n\u2022Dead player: Onryo blows out flames more
         \nMore dead players increase frequency
         \nNo dead players: same as other ghosts
       \n\n\u2022 less than 60% sanity: more flame blowing, hunting attempt
    </string>
    <string name="RaijuDesc">A Raiju thrives on electrical current, siphoning power from devices. It can be agitated by excess power.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: A Raiju can move faster by siphoning power from electrical devices.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Constantly disrupts electronic equipment, making it easier to track.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
       \n\n\u2022 Faster speed near on electronics: 65% with electronics on, 50% without
        \n\n\u2022 Range of speed increase: 6m on small maps, 8m on medium, 10m on large
        \n\n\u2022 Hunt malfunctions electronics: at 15m for Raiju, compare to 10m others
       \n\n\u2022  Prevent early hunts: by removing extra turned on electronics, avoid discarding them on ground during hunts.
        \n\n\u2022 Watch Raiju and Myling speed near electronics to avoid confusion
    </string>
    <string name="TheTwinsDesc">These ghosts mimic each other\'s actions, alternating their attacks to confuse their prey.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Either Twin can initiate an attack on their prey.
        \n\nWeaknesses: The Twins often interact with the environment simultaneously.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Can interact with multiple objects in different rooms simultaneously
        \n\n\u2022 Varied speeds heard during multiple hunts
        \n\n\u2022 Twins may release a slightly faster (110%) or slower (90%) ghost during a hunt
        \n\n\u2022 Only one ghost sent out during a hunt
        \n\n\u2022 Can hunt from a different location using a "decoy" twin

    </string>
    <string name="TheMimicDesc">The Mimic is an elusive, mysterious, copycat ghost that mirrors traits and behaviors from others, including other ghost types.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Uncertain capabilities. Treat a Mimic as if it had every possible modifier.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Ghost orb sightings near mimics.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 The Mimic provides "evidence" of Ghost Orbs in addition to its three main evidence types.
        \n Mimic: orbs + 3 (2 on Nightmare) evidences.
        \n\n\u2022 Orbs always present on Nightmare Mode.
        \n\n\u2022 Orbs with no evidence.
        \n\n\u2022 With orbs, always check other evidence to confirm no mimic.
        \n\n\u2022 Treat a Mimic as if it had every possible modifier is the safest way to handle it.
        \n Mimics change ghosts every 30s-2min.
       \n\n\u2022 Behavior won\'t change mid-hunt.
        \nChanging behavior? Check for mimic.
        \n\n\u2022 Minimize speaking near the ghost (Yokai).
        \n\n\u2022 Turn off unnecessary electronics (Raiju).
        \n\n\u2022Keep the lights on in the Ghost Room (Mare).
        \n\n\u2022 Have a source of flame in the Ghost Room (Onryo).
        \\n\n\u2022 Be prepared for possible early hunts (Demon).</string>
    <string name="DeogenDesc">Surrounded by fog, Deogen elude ghost hunters. They find hidden prey and stalk them into exhaustion.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Deogen sense the living and move quickly with no player in sight.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Require energy to form, move slowly when approaching victims
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Deogen\'s hunt sanity threshold: 40%, not 50%.
        \n\n\u2022 Can\'t hide from it.
         \n\n\u2022 Distinct growl/Heavy breath spirit box response.
        \n Deogen maintains continuous line-of-sight during hunts, shifting targets periodically. Incense can temporarily redirect it.
        \n\n\u2022 Listen to speed change while hiding if it slows down approaching players.
        \n Beware of similar behaviors from young Thaye, Revenant, or Hantu.
        \n Choose hiding spots that allow easy escape or prepare Incense.
        \n\n\u2022 Slow near you, easy to loop.
        \n\n\u2022 More writing and dots chances.
        \n\n\u2022 Spirit box always on in Nightmare
        \n\n\u2022 Stunning with smudge sticks maintains slowed speed.
    </string>
    <string name="MoroiDesc">Moroi drain energy from the living and place curses, curable by antidotes or distance.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Stronger with weaker victims, faster at low player sanity.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Hyperosmia weakens them for longer periods, smudge sticks blind them longer during hunts.
    \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 High speed Speed Demon ghost.
        \n\n\u2022 Curses on spirit box or parabolic mic response.
        \n\n\u2022 Curse doubles sanity drain, light/candles don\'t prevent it.
        \n\n\u2022 Remove curse with sanity pills.
        \n\n\u2022 Hunt-blind smudge Time: 12s (Moroi), 6s (others).
        \n\n\u2022 Lower sanity = faster Moroi.
        \n\n\u2022 Can Test by: Using Spirit box + light/candle, If sanity draining = Moroi.
        \n\n\u2022 No-evidence: Faster Moroi as sanity drops.
        \n\n\u2022 Line-of-sight speed boost, fastest at 0% sanity.
        \n\n\u2022 Spirit box forced evidence on Nightmare.
        \n\n\u2022 Listen for speed shifts during hunts or as sanity drops.
        \n\n\u2022 Use sanity meds to slow it down during hunts.
        \n\n\u2022 Use sanity monitor to detect excessive sanity drain.
    </string>
    <string name="ThayeDesc">Thaye rapidly age and deteriorate when near the living. They become active and agile when entering a location.
        \n\nUnique Strengths: Active, defensive, and agile when entering the location.
        \n\nWeaknesses: Weaken over time, becoming slower and quieter with prolonged exposure to the living.
        \n\nTips &amp; Tricks
        \n\n\u2022 Early Hunter: Hunts at 75%
        \n\n\u2022 Unique aging ability
            \n Starts young, aggressive, fast (2.5m/s),
            \n Ages near you every 1-2 mins, slower at old age (15%, 1m/s)
        \n\n\u2022 No speed increase when Thayes see you during a hunt
        \n\n\u2022 Monitor hunt speed to identify Thaye
        \n If it appears to decrease in speed during hunts, it\'s probably a Thaye.
          \n\n\u2022  Ouija board age changes with aging
        \n\n\u2022 No D.O.T.S Projector within a few minutes = Thaye less likely.
       \n\n\u2022 If Ghost gives Ghost Writing + D.O.T.S Projector on Nightmare = Thaye (Deogen has guaranteed Spirit Box).

    </string>
</resources>